Uzair Imtiaz

Professional Summary

Senior Python Developer offering 6+ years of extensive experience and exceptional analytical and critical thinking skills. I cater projects with a proactive approach, great work ethic, and the important ability to function well in fast-paced and deadline-driven team environments.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python 2.5-2.7/3.4-3.6, SQL and PL/SQL.

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, DOM, SAX, Java Script, jQuery, AJAX, XML.

Frameworks: Django, PyJamas, Flask, Jython, Pyramid, CherryPy

Version Control: MVC, SVN, CVS, Git, GitHub.

Front End: ReactJS, Angular, jQuery, Ajax, ExtJS, JSON, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML

Databases: Oracle, My SQL, PostgreSQL, Apache Cassandra

Testing Tools: PyTest, Testify, Selenium, and JIRA.

Professional Experience

Alsyke Technologies Team Lead / SSE June 2020 – Jan 2020 Responsibilities:

- Working as Team Lead and have following main responsibilities:
 - Client communication and on-site engagement with clients for gathering their business requirements and solution implementation.
 - Component and routing development in Front-end Application with React.
 - Worked on the improvement of data protection and security and created new user information solutions
 - Develop architecture for Micro-services in Django and deployments with Docker.
 - Defining API specifications for financial transactions.
 - Flexible to work in either Development & Support projects.
 - Responsible for debugging the project monitored on JIRA (Agile)
 - Wrote Python scripts to parse JSON documents and load the data in the database.
 - Worked on Restful API's to access the third-party data for the internal analysis and statistical representation of data.

Tools and Environment: Python, Django 1.3, MySQL, Linux, HTML, XHTML, SVN, CSS, AJAX, JavaScript, Apache Web Server, ReactJS, PostgreSQL, DRF, SOAP, and AWS, S3.

Mtech.

Senior Software Engineer Mar 2017 – Jun 2020 Responsibilities:

• Working as **Team Member** and have following main responsibilities:

- Worked on development of an internal testing tool framework written in Python.
- Developed GUI using Python and Django for dynamically displaying block documentation and other features of python code using a web browser.
- Wrote scripts in Python for extracting data from HTML files.
- Developed views and templates with Python and Django view controllers and templating language to create a user-friendly website interface.
- Used JavaScript and JSON to update a portion of a webpage.
- Performed troubleshooting, fixed and deployed many bug fixes for applications that were a main source of data for both customers and internal customer service team.
- Handled potential points of failure (database, communication points and file system errors)
 through error handling and communication of failure.

Tools and Environment: ReactJS, Diango, PostgreSQL, SOAP, and AWS, S3.

Tune.pk.
Full Stack Engineer
Mar 2015 – Feb 2017
Responsibilities:

- Working as Team Member and have following main responsibilities:
 - Worked on requirement gathering and High-level design.
 - Used HTML/CSS, XML and JavaScript for UI development.
 - Converted Visual Basic Application to Python, MySQL.
 - Used python scripts to update content in the database and manipulate files.
 - Created Reports using JASPER.
 - Performed research regarding Python Programming and its uses and efficiency.
 - Utilized Python in the handling of all hits on Django, Redis, and other applications.
 - Followed Agile Methodology and SCRUM Process.
 - Extensive code reviewing using GitHub pull requests, improved code quality, and conducted meetings among peer.

Tools and Environment: Python, Django, Java Script, XML, JASPER, QTP, MySQL, PL/SQL, Oracle.

Education

BCS (Computer Science), PUCIT

Contact Details:

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-uzair-a405a41a5/

Email: uzairimtiaz44@gmail.com

Mobile #: +92-334-7997557

Location: Lahore(54000), Pakistan

Projects:

- NamePress is a robust T-Shirt Design platform that uses AI to enhance the design pattern of printing. It has a highly dynamic and interactive environment.

Namepress: https://namepress.com/

- Robotify is a code learning platform for beginners. It Jumpstarts your kid's career! Mastering Math, Critical Thinking and Coding the best option for beginner coders.

Robotify: https://robotify.com

- edX is a learning platform such as Udemy, you will be able to take available different courses from various universities on this platform:

edX: https://www.edx.org/

- When you need to hire someone a landscaper, a DJ, anyone Thumbtack finds them for you for free. Thumbtack: https://thumbtack.com
- The Crypto WZRD Platform is custom built with each member in mind on everything they'll need to get started with Cryptocurrency.

CryptoWZRD: https://cryptowzrd.com

- DAPS Coin- Web Wallet: https://web-wallet.dapscoin.com/ https://www.loom.com/share/13c3db6b666d42fe82513543831bbafe

Login Seed: gravity pigeon tackle village oak more film solar appear nephew cable brave twenty must story recycle jar peanut forget rule winter digital like law